Evgenii Kazmiruk

Krasnovarsk, Russia

Borisova, 30 – 16 Krasnoyarsk, Russia 660074 Phone: +7-913-513-94-85 kazmiruk.evgeniy@gmail.com

I am a software developer and engineer with strong technical background and 6 years of experience. I have an ability to work with minimum of supervision during developing and good communication skills. I enjoy of developing complex systems which require non-trivial approaches and solutions. I am seeking an opportunity to expand my career into large-scale business-oriented applications develop.

TECHNICAL SKILLS (see more details at the last page)

Platforms: Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), Windows

Languages: Python, PHP, JavaScript, Java, CoffeeScritp, TypeScript

DBMS: PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Technologies/tools: Git, Svn, Jira, XML, json, sql, HTML (+HTML5), CSS(+CSS3), jquery, AngularJs

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TopSoft, LLC, Moscow, Russia

Development Team Leader(Remote)

Nov 2013 – Present

The company has several different projects that were built in different time and with different approaches and technologies. Differences between this sites and a lot of work for supporting forced the company to start development of common platform for such projects. I am involved in design architecture, develop and test of social-like platform for projects of the company. First several month my task was to choose technologies and create a prototype. After that I developed the production ready platform on such stack of technologies as Python + Django, PostgreSQL as DBMS, Redis as Key-Value storage, gearman for asynchronous tasks and AngularJs on frontend. After that I developed migrate tool for mapping old data structure on new tables. Currently all projects of the company successfully transferred into this platform and I continue to support and develop backend engine for new purposes of company.

Development Environment: Linux (Ubuntu), Python 2.7, wsgi, uwsgi + nginx, WebDAV, Django 1.6, gevent, PostgreSQL 9.x, Redis, Gearman, javascript, socket.io, AngularJs, jquery, HTML5, CSS3, LESS, git

Sithi, LLC, Krasnoyarsk, Russia

Nov 2011 - Jun 2014

Senior Python Developer

The company specialized in social networks for children in different countries (Russia, GB, Spain, Czech Republic, Estonia, Vietnam). My task was in building horizontal scaling and fault-tolerance architecture. I used Python and Flask to develop web application with REST api for communication with client on Flash (ActionScript) and mobile applications. Also I developed HTML version of the site. Also it was a lot of task for optimization of queries to MySQL database, caching and refactoring of legacy code. I built socket.io server on base of redis, websockets and gevent library for mobile applications..

Development Environment: Linux (Ubuntu), Unix (FreeBSD), Python 2.7, uwsgi + nginx, Flask, MySQL 5.x, Memcache, Redis, javascript, gevent, socket.io, jquery, HTML5, CSS3, svn, actionscript

Factor, LLC, Krasnoyarsk, Russia

May 2011 - Nov 2011

Deputy chief of software development department (adviser)

Toward the moment when I was hired the company had an online shop mediator of Taobao. This system was built on base of Joomla CMS and faced with high loads. I introduced MongoDB into system for storing goods information and sharding with replication as first measure to withstand high load. After that I developed online shop on Python and Django with optimizations of data structures and sql queries. Also I built third party library for auto

caching of objects in django. For load balancing was applied nginx as frontend. The result of this work was in increasing of online users pick value from 3,000 till 60,000.

Development Environment: Linux (Ubuntu, Debian), PHP 5.x, Python 2.7, uwsgi + nginx, php-fpm + nginx, Django 1.4, MongoDB 2.x, Redis, Joomla, MySQL 5.x, javascript, HTML, CSS, jquery, svn

TelecomConsulting, LLC, Krasnoyarsk, Russia

Feb 2010 - May 2011

Software Developer

My task was in developing different projects of the company and building of infrastructure tools for main company system. I developed two small online-shops on Joomla, content service for internet providers. After that I was involved into developing of the main company project – aggregation system for tenders based on Yii framework. My task was in developing of system to parse data about tenders from different sites, structurize it and store in MySQL in suitable structure. Parsers were written with Python. Also I developed CRM system for internal usage based on php, Zend Framework and MySQL. For the CRM system I built parsers to collect information about clients from internal documents.

Development Environment: Linux (Ubuntu), Unix (FreeBSD), PHP 5.x, Python 2.6, php-fpm + nginx, apache2, Memcache, MySQL 5.x, Joomla, WordPress, ZendFramework, Yii, javascript, HTML, CSS, jquery, svn

EDUCATION

2013 - MS, Computer Science, GPA: 5.0

Siberian State Aerospace University, Krasnoyarsk, Russia Graduated with honors

Key Technical Skills (in order of aptitude)

Skill	Professional Experience	Experience Level	Last Used
Python 2.7	5 years	Advanced	Currently Used

- Experience working with stackless python
- Experience working with python OO patterns

Frameworks

- Django: Experience working with built-in modules, building scalable apps, extending of framework
- Flask: Experience working with built-in modules, building scalable apps, extending of framework
- Gevent: Experience working with coroutine-based network library for building non-blocking servers
- SQLAlchemy: Experience using with Flask framework

PHP 5.x	3 years	Advanced	2011

- Experience working with both procedural and OO, pattern-oriented PHP
- Experience working with extending core PHP classes
- Experience writing database-backend, MVC-based PHP applications

Frameworks/CMS:

- Wordpress: installation, configuration, writing extensions
- Joomla: installation, configuration, writing extensions
- Zend Framework: building MVC-based applications, writing extensions
- Yii: building MVC-based applications, writing extensions

MySQL 5.x	3 years	Advanced	2011

- Experience designing complex, normalized and denormalized schemas
- Experience creating triggers, stored procedures, events, defining indexes and foreign key constraints for referential integrity

- Experienced primarily with MyISAM and InnoDB engines
- Experience writing and optimizing complex queries on tables with more than 50,000,000 rows

PostgreSQL 9.x 2 years Advanced Currently Used

- Experience designing complex, normalized and denormalized schemas
- Experience creating triggers, stored procedures, defining indexes and constraints for referential integrity
- Experience writing and optimizing complex queries on tables with more than 20,000,000 rows

Redis 5 years Advanced Currently Used

- Experience working with creating efficient cache structures
- Experience working with pub\sub
- Experience using of twemproxy for building a clusters

JavaScript 5 years Advanced Currently Used

- Experience working with pure javascript
- Experience using of closures, prototype-oriented model
- Experience writing cross-browser scripts
- Experience using of canvas and WebGL technologies
- Experience using of compiled languages CoffeeScript and TypeScript

Frameworks:

- AngularJS: Experience building of rich internet applications
- ¡Query: Experience of using selectors, ui, writing plugins
- LibCanvas: Experience writing applications with isometric graphic

MongoDB 3 years Advanced 2011

- Experience in building of shared and replicated clusters
- Experience writing queries with using of aggregation and map-reduce framework
- Experience writing and optimizing complex queries on tables with more than 5,000,000 rows
- Experience working with atomic operations
- Certificates «MongoDB for developers» and «MongoDB for administrators»

Memcache 3 years Advanced 2011

- Experience working with creating of efficient cache structures
- Experience building of clusters with consistent hash as master key

HTML, CSS 5 years Advanced Currently Used

- Experience writing valid, semantic XHTML
- HTML minimalist
- Experience with complex CSS selectors, pseudo-elements, etc.
- Experience with CSS browser compatibility issues and workarounds
- Experience with LESS language

Frameworks:

- Experience working with Twitter Bootstrap